Finding Aid for Edwin S. George Reserve (Mich.) records, 1924-2013
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Research
  - Insects
    - Various Orders
      - Orthoptera
        - Gangwere and Evans Grasshopper Study Project 1964-1965 (Box 7)
        - General circa 1963-1965 (Box 7)
        - Grasshopper Population Project 1964-1965 (Box 7)
        - Notes on Species circa 1949-1950 (Box 7)
        - Orthoptera Population Estimation -- Evans Old Field 1964-1965 (Box 7)
        - Orthoptera Studies -- Gangwere, S. K. 1959-1964 (Box 7)
        - Photographs undated (Box 7)
        - Weights and Biomass 1957-1959 (Box 7)
      - Philaenus 1966 (Box 7)
      - Philaenus -- Numbers and Density 1957-1959 (Box 7)
      - Scelio Photographs 1957 (Box 7)
      - Sphecidae -- Evans Old Field 1983 (Box 7)
      - Tenthredinidae Ichneumonidae circa 1961-1971 (Box 7)
    - Weights of Species 1961-1966 (Box 7)
  - Plants
    - ESGR (Box 8)
      - "The Flora of the Edwin S. George Reserve Livingston Co., Mich.," 1943 (Box 8)
      - Hectare Plot -- Southwest Woods 1956 (Box 8)
      - Herbarium Record Books 1941-1967 (Box 8)
      - Plant Survey 1951-1996 (Box 8)
      - "A Preliminary List of the Vascular Plants of the Edwin S. George Reserve, Livingston County, Michigan," Arthur W. Cooper 1961 (Box 8)
      - Vegetation Data Sheets -- ESGR 1957, 2 folders (Box 8)
      - West Woods 1956 (Box 8)
    - Evans Old Field (EOF)
      - Annual/Biennial vs. Perennials 1948-1995 (Box 8)
      - Changes in Plants 1949-1990 (Box 8)
      - Clip Quadrats 1949-1959 (Box 8)
      - Community Strata -- Plant Heights circa 1952 (Box 8)
      - Community Strata -- Vegetation 1954-1970 (Box 8)
      - Deer Grazing of Plants 1990 (Box 8)
      - Denuded Quadrats 1950 (Box 8)
      - Distribution and Abundance 1979-1995 (Box 8)
      - Distribution Patterns 1953 (Box 8)
      - Ecological Importance 1970 (Box 8)
      - Field Notes for Vegetation Samples, R2, F14, and F20 1964 (Box 8)
      - Field Visit Records 1948-1996 (Box 8)
      - Frequency and Density 1949 (Box 8)
      - Frequency Cover Survey 1983 (Box 8)
      - Frequency Surveys
        - 1949 (Box 8)
        - 1951 (Box 8)
        - 1953 (Box 8)
        - 1964 (Box 8)
        - 1974 (Box 8)
        - Analysis 1953-1974 (Box 8)
      - Grasses and Forbs Analysis 1953-1981 (Box 8)
      - Higher Plant Notes and Statistics 1948-1991 (Box 8)
      - Initial Plants 1948-1954 (Box 8)
      - Inventories
        - Evans Old Field Plant Inventories 1949-1974 (Box 8)
        - Evans Old Field Plant Inventories 1972-1996 (Box 8)
        - Higher Plants 1948-1996 (Box 8)
        - Population Censuses -- Trees and Shrubs 1950-1983 (Box 8)
      - Life Forms of Evans Old Field Plants 1948-1995 (Box 8)
      - Life History Studies 1951-1954 (Box 8)
      - Native vs. Introduced Plants 1949-1995 (Box 8)
      - Permanent Quadrats 1950-1954 (Box 8)
      - Persistence vs. Failure to Establish 1974-1995 (Box 8)
      - Phenology 1948-1953 (Box 8)
      - Phenology -- Growth Stage 1954 (Box 8)
      - Phenology 1971 (Box 8)
      - Plant Biomass 1964-1965 (Box 8)
      - Plant Notes
        - A-C 1948-1997 (Box 8)
        - D-J 1948-1997 (Box 8)
        - K-P 1948-1997 (Box 8)
        - Q-V 1948-1997 (Box 8)
      - Plant Species Census 1949-1983 (Box 8)
      - Plant Succession on Evans Old Field 1956-1983 (Box 8)
      - Plants 1st Recorded After 1954, 1992-1994 (Box 8)
      - Point Quadrat Studies R2 and F14 1967, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Point Quadrat Studies with P.J.R. Hill 1954 (Box 9)
      - Preferred Habitats 1970-1981 (Box 9)
      - Productivity 1950-1975 (Box 9)
      - Rare and Extinct Plants 1965-1995 (Box 9)
      - Relative Abundance 1948-1995 (Box 9)
      - Roadway Data 1965-1985 (Box 9)
      - Species and Area 1953 (Box 9)
      - Species and Genus 1955 (Box 9)
      - Species Richness (Diversity) 1948-1992 (Box 9)
      - Swale Data 1949-1983 (Box 9)
      - Vegetation Data 1957-1961 (Box 9)
      - Vegetation Photos 1954 (Box 9)
      - Vegetation Photos -- Types 1954 (Box 9)
      - Vegetation Types 1954-1956 (Box 9)
      - Vegetation Types Study with E. Dahl 1953 (Box 9)
    - Flowering Periods 1972-1973 (Box 15)
    - Evans Old Field Plant Database 1948-1997, .ZIP file containing Filemaker and Excel files
  - Projects
    - Alphabetical
      - A-G 1972-1980 (Box 9)
      - H-O 1972-1980 (Box 9)
      - P-W 1972-1980 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence
      - A-L 1958-1980 (Box 9)
      - M-Z 1957-1972 (Box 9)
      - "Diversity and Pattern in Plants and Animals" Correspondence 1964-1997 (Box 9)
      - Evans-Murdoch Correspondence on Homoptera 1965-1971 (Box 9)
      - Evans and Murdoch Correspondence and Notes -- Taxonomic Composition Paper 1967 (Box 9)
    - Projects by Researcher
      - Blair circa 1938 (Box 9)
      - Brand, R.H. 1952-1954 (Box 9)
      - Congdon Turtle Project 1983-1985 (Box 9)
      - Dice, ca. 1947Evans, Francis C. circa 1948 (Box 9)
      - Evans, Francis C. -- Structure and Composition of Insect Communities 1956-1964 (Box 9)
      - Gangwere, S.K. -- Orthoptera Proposal 1979-1980 (Box 9)
      - Graham, J.M. 1968 (Box 9)
      - Greenberg, Robert E.
        - Exclosure Study 1964 (Box 9)
        - Exclosure Study Plot I 1951-1954 (Box 9)
        - Exclosure Study Plot II 1951-1954 (Box 9)
        - Exclosure Study Plot III 1951-1954 (Box 9)
        - Exclosure Study Plot IV 1951-1954 (Box 9)
      - Greenberg, Robert E. (cont.)
        - Exclosure Study Plot V 1951-1954 (Box 9)
        - Exclosure Study Plot VI 1951-1954 (Box 9)
      - Hamerstrom 1943-1947 (Box 10)
      - Hight, M.E. 1965-1968 (Box 10)
      - Hill, Peter J.R. circa 1956 (Box 10)
      - Howard, Walter E. 1942 (Box 10)
      - Kodric, Astrid -- Dragonflies undated (Box 10)
      - McCammon, James undated (Box 10)
      - McCullough, Dale R. 1967-1980 (Box 10)
      - McNeil, Richard, 1960-1961 Metzger, Lee H. 1964 (Box 10)
      - Mitchell, Rodger 1964-1965 (Box 10)
      - Pruitt, Wm. O. Jr. -- Field Data Including Temperature Records and Trapping Records 1952-1953 (Box 10)
      - Rittschof, Daniel 1968 (Box 10)
      - Shetron, Stephen G. 1963 (Box 10)
      - Simpson, Rachel -- Evans Plant Data Proposal 1996 (Box 10)
      - Talbot, Mary 1961-1979 (Box 10)
      - Thompson, William L. 1964-1968 (Box 10)
      - Wenner, Adrian -- Research 1959 (Box 10)
      - Wise, David H. 1968 (Box 10)
    - Proposals 1963-1979 (Box 10)
    - Research Activities 1931-1974 (Box 10)
    - Summary of Work 1957-1958 (Box 10)
  - Weather Records
    - Daily Weather Records
      - 1951-1955, 3 folders (Box 10)
      - 1956-1958, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - 1959 (Box 10)
      - 1960 (Box 10)
      - 1961 (Box 10)
      - 1962 (Box 10)
      - 1963 (Box 10)
      - 1964 (Box 10)
      - 1965 (Box 10)
      - 1966 (Box 10)
      - 1967 (Box 10)
      - 1968 (Box 11)
      - 1969 (Box 11)
      - 1970 (Box 11)
      - 1971 (Box 11)
      - 1972 (Box 11)
      - 1973 (Box 11)
      - 1974 (Box 11)
      - 1975 (Box 11)
      - 1976 (Box 11)
      - 1977 (Box 11)
      - 1978 (Box 11)
    - Equipment 1950-1963 (Box 11)
    - ESGR Weather 1948-1966 (Box 11)
    - ESGR Weather -- Miscellaneous Calculations, Francis C. Evans 1942-1953 (Box 11)
    - Evans Microclimatology Talk 1962 (Box 11)
    - Meteorological Data collected by N.G. Hairston, Evans Old Field 1949-1950 (Box 11)
    - Meteorological Project, Meteorology Class, Fall 1966 (Box 11)
    - Meteorology Program 1966 (Box 11)
    - Micrometeorological Field Station 1958-1966 (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous Records 1949-1974 (Box 11)
    - Monthly Weather Summaries
      - 1949-1954 (Box 11)
      - 1955-1962 (Box 11)
      - 1963-1968 (Box 11)
      - 1969-1974 (Box 11)
      - 1974-1981 (Box 11)
    - Study Area Meteorology 1949-1959 (Box 11)
    - Water Data 1949-1952 (Box 11)
    - Water Level Records
      - 1950-1959 (Box 11)
      - 1960-1974 (Box 11)
      - 1975-1979 (Box 11)
    - Weather Data 1949-1954 (Box 11)
- Deer Herd
  The Deer Herd series (0.75 linear feet), 1934-2005, contains records specific to the Edwin S. George Reserve's Deer Program. Begun in 1928 with six deer, the herd had expanded to 160 within five years. In 1942, the Reserve began conducting an annual cropping of the herd to reduce browsing pressure on the vegetation. Deer harvest records, as well as records on the management of the deer program, are included in this series.
  - Cervidae Facility Requirements 1988-2005 (Box 12)
  - Deer Harvests 1951-1965 (Box 12)
  - Deer Herd Information 1947-1981 (Box 12)
  - Deer Program 1965-1980 (Box 12)
  - Deer Skulls (Aged by Severinghaus) 1950 (Box 12)
  - Department of Conservation Fence and License Requirements 1962-1963 (Box 12)
  - Department of Natural Resources 1982-2000 (Box 12)
  - Fatality Control Literature 1997-2002 (Box 12)
  - Fawn Locations 1956 (Box 12)
  - Game Breeders License 1980-1995 (Box 12)
  - Harvest Instructions 1939-1973 (Box 12)
  - Health Reports 1962-2001 (Box 12)
  - Herd Composition, Food Habits, etc. 1946-1947 (Box 12)
  - Live Sale Correspondence 1959-1980 (Box 12)
  - McCullough, Dale -- Deer Program 1967-1979 (Box 12)
  - Michigan Department of Agriculture 2001 (Box 12)
  - Museum Catalogue of Deer Killed 1934-1966 (Box 12)
  - Photographs -- Deer Harvest circa 1961 (Box 12)
  - Photographs of Deer Drive by Doug Fulton, Ann Arbor News 1963-1965 (Box 12)
  - Physiology of Reproduction 1947-1948 (Box 12)
  - Publications and Papers 1948-1967 (Box 12)
  - State Game Division Pellet Count 1959-1964 (Box 12)
  - Venison Sales -- Correspondence 1956-1999 (Box 12)
  - Venison Sales -- Flyers 1959-1998 (Box 12)
  - Venison Sales -- Lists 1948-1969 (Box 12)
  - Weights 1941-1948 (Box 12)
- Maps
  The Maps series (0.25 linear feet plus oversize materials), 1929-2010, includes various types of maps of the Reserve, such as vegetation maps, soil maps, grid maps, contour maps, and cover maps. The series also includes oversize materials, and in some cases, maps may exist in multiple sizes.
  - Cover Maps 1933-1936 (Box 12)
  - The Edwin S. George Reserve by Timothy Howard 1996-1998 (Box 12)
  - Edwin S. George Reserve Contour Map, Ruskin and Hickie 1933-1934 (Box 12)
  - Evans Old Field Grid Stake Locations 1949-1953 (Box 12)
  - Government Land Office 1828 Survey Notes for ESGR copied by F.N. Hamerstrom Jr. and F. Hamerstrom, undated (Box 12)
  - Grid Maps 1950-1963 (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous Maps 1952, 1979 undated (Box 12)
  - Place Names and Locations 1997 undated (Box 12)
  - Ponds 1954-1970 (Box 12)
  - Soil Maps undated (Box 12)
  - Edwin S. George Reserve
    - Boundary Survey -- E.S. George Reserve 2010 (3 sheets) (Map-case 307, Folder 1)
    - Cover Map, Edwin S. George Reserve -- H.H. Wight 1935 (Map-case 307, Folder 1)
    - Cover Map of the Edwin S. George Reserve 1948 (Map-case 307, Folder 1)
    - The Edwin S. George Reserve by Timothy Howard 1998 (Map-case 307, Folder 1)
    - Edwin S. George Reserve -- Preliminary Draft by Timothy Howard circa 1998 (Map-case 307, Folder 1)
    - Edwin S. George Reserve Contour Map, University Museums, University of Michigan, Ruskin and Hickie 1933-1934 (Map-case 307, Folder 1)
    - E.S. George Reserve Deer Fence Installation 1986-1987 (Map-case 307, Folder 1)
    - E.S. George Reserve Sections 19 and 20, Putnam Twp., Livingston Co 1987 (Map-case 307, Folder 1)
    - Land-Feature Types, E.S. George Reserve (Map-case 307, Folder 1)
    - Pond Maps
      - Burt Pond 1958 (Map-case 307, Folder 2)
      - Crane Pond cloth tracing 1953 (Map-case 307, Folder 2)
      - Crane Pond 1953-1954 (Map-case 307, Folder 2)
      - George Pond 1954 (Map-case 307, Folder 2)
      - Little West Woods Pond 1954 (Map-case 307, Folder 2)
      - Southwest Woods Pond 1970 (Map-case 307, Folder 2)
      - West Woods Pond 1954 (Map-case 307, Folder 2)
      - Livingston County Soils: ESGR Closeup 2000 (Map-case 307, Folder 3)
      - Soils of the E.S. George Reserve after James O. Veatch (1953) 2000 (Map-case 307, Folder 3)
      - Soil Map by J.O. Veatch 1953 (Map-case 307, Folder 3)
      - Soil Map by J.O. Veatch -- cloth tracing 1953 (Map-case 307, Folder 3)
      - Soil Map of the Edwin S. George Reserve (Map-case 307, Folder 3)
      - Soil Map of the Edwin S. George Reserve -- O.H. Lovejoy 1940 (Map-case 307, Folder 3)
      - Soil Map of the Edwin S. George Reserve, Livingston County, Michigan 1972 (Map-case 307, Folder 3)
      - Soils Map by S.G. Shetron -- May 1963 Mapped Aerial Photographs, 1955 (Map-case 307, Folder 3)
      - Soil Survey by Stephen G. Shetron 1963 (Map-case 307, Folder 3)
    - Survey of Land for Col. Edwin S. George 1929 (Map-case 307, Folder 3)
    - Untitled Hand Drawn map of ESGR (Map-case 307, Folder 3)
    - Vegetation Cover Type Map of the Edwin S. George Reserve (includes legend) 1972 (Map-case 307, Folder 3)
  - Fresh Air Camp
    - Fresh Air Camp (Map-case 307, Folder 4)
    - Map of Part of Unadilla and Putnam Townships Showing U. of M. S.C.A. Fresh Air Camp 1930 (Map-case 307, Folder 4)
    - Topographic Survey of Fresh Air Camp 1948; revised 1959 (Map-case 307, Folder 4)
    - Topographical Map Showing Location of University of Michigan Student Christian Association Fresh Air Camp 1929 (Map-case 307, Folder 4)
  - Livingston County
    - Gregory Quadrangle, Michigan, U.S. Department of the Interior Geological Survey 1974 (Map-case 307, Folder 4)
    - Land Ownership Map, Washtenaw and Livingston Counties (Map-case 307, Folder 4)
    - Livingston County, Michigan Department of Conservation (Map-case 307, Folder 4)
    - Pinckney Quadrangle, Michigan, U.S. Department of the Interior Geological Survey 1983 (Map-case 307, Folder 4)
    - Survey of a Parcel of Land: Section 24, 19, 20, 25, 30, 29 Town I North Range 3-4 East Unadilla and Putnam Townships, Livingston County, Michigan 1986 (Map-case 307, Folder 4)
    - Survey of a Parcel of Land -- Coordinate Point Worksheet: Section 24, 19, 20, 25, 30, 29 Town I North Range 3-4 East Unadilla and Putnam Townships, Livingston County, Michigan 1986 (Map-case 307, Folder 4)
    - Washtenaw County Sharon County Parts of Sections 29 and 30 (Sharon Hollow) (Map-case 307, Folder 4)
- Photographs 1924-1991
  The Photographs series (1 linear foot plus oversize materials), 1924-1991, documents the Edwin S. George reserve in photographs. Pictures of the Reserve land, buildings, wildlife, and staff and researchers are included. Another component of the series is the aerial photographs of the Reserve, some of which were used in creating maps of the area. The aerial photographs often have the date and negative number printed on the picture. For example, 11-8-55 indicates that the picture was taken November 8, 1955, while XQ-3P-49 seems to indicate the negative number. The series also contains oversize materials and some aerial photographs may include copies in multiple sizes.
  - Construction of Ponds undated (Box 13)
  - ESGR Photographs
    - Aerial Photographs 1940-1961 (Box 13)
    - Aerial Photographs 1958 (Box 13)
    - Aerial Photographs -- Correspondence 1949-1979 (Box 13)
    - Album 1936-1938 (Box 13)
    - Evans, Francis C. Photos 1953-1963 (Box 13)
    - Low Altitude Coverage 1965 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs 1955-1991, undated (Box 13)
    - Negatives June 24, 1958 (Box 13)
    - Photos and Negatives 1939 (Box 13)
    - Photos and Negatives June 26, 1958 (Box 13)
    - Stereograms (Aerial Photographs) from Lee Miller 1965 (Box 13)
  - Graham, W.J. 1967-1968 (Box 13)
  - Ground Truth, Visible Prints and Infrared Prints for Mud Lake Bog 1964 (Box 13)
  - Museum of Zoology -- New Wing Opening 1964 (Box 13)
  - Negative Albums, 4 volumes (Box 13)
  - Nest Eggs -- George Sutton 1974 (Box 13)
  - People
    - Camburn, Lawrence (Larry) 1953-1965 (Box 13)
    - Hatt, R.T. and others (including N.A. Wood, Frank & Mrs. Blair, J. Van Tyne, W.H. Burt, James Oliver, F. M. Gaige, Calvin Goodrich, Cecil Billington, Carl Huble, and Charles Creaser) 1924, 1938 (Box 13)
    - Hubbell, Theodore H. undated (Box 13)
    - Sutton, Dr. George M. undated (Box 13)
    - Tinkle, Donald W. undated (Box 13)
  - Pruitt Photographs and Negatives undated (Box 13)
  - Reverse Infrared Photograph undated
    - Abrams Aerial Survey 1936 (Map-case 308, Folder 1)
    - Abrams Aerial Survey/USDA Survey Aerial Photographs 1940 (Map-case 308, Folder 2)
    - Grid Photograph and Negative 1963-1969 (Map-case 308, Folder 3)
    - Infrared Aerial Photographs undated (Map-case 308, Folder 4)
    - USDA Aerial Photographs 1940-1970, 3 folders
      - USDA Aerial Photographs 1940-1970 (Map-case 308, Folder 5)
      - USDA Aerial Photographs 1940-1970 (Map-case 308, Folder 6)
        (continued)
      - USDA Aerial Photographs 1940-1970 (Map-case 308, Folder 7)
    - Detroit Edison Co. Aerial Photographs 1950 (Map-case 308, Folder 8)
  - Slides (Box 14)
- Archived Website
  - Archived Edwin S. George Reserve website 2013-[ongoing]
    The Archived Website series, 2013-[ongoing], documents the academic programs, accomplishments, resources, events, and people at the Edwin S. George Reserve. Content includes important news and announcements, publications, and information about the location, facilities, research projects, use, data resources, and the overall mission of the Reserve. This archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/.